AJAY RANWA

Kuchaman City, Rajasthan · 6378337598 Email-ID· LinkedIn Profile · GitHub

IT Professional with experience of working with Engineers and have good hands-on Languages which helps me to get practical knowledge. I have Experience working as a Campus Ambassador which highlights my Leadership qualities and communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2021-PRESENT

HUMAN RESOURCES ASSISTANT RECRUITER, AASHMAN FOUNDATION

INTERNSHIP

Helping Aashman foundation to get volunteers for various job positions. Like, HR, Sales and Marketing, Video Editing, Social Media Marketing, and many more.

MAY 2021- JUNE 2021

DATA SCIENCE & BUSINESS ANALYTICS, THE SPARKS FOUNDATION

INTERNSHIP

Things we perform here are to collect data and train a machine with that data and predict the outcomes with the test data.

Our works include day-to-day tasks performed.

JAN 2021 - FEB 2021

CAMPUS AMBASSADOR, EDFOUL

INTERNSHIP

Helped our team to build various kinds of LEDs they were working on. Gained good communication skills and came up with a good leadership quality.

NOV 2020 - DEC 2021

VOLUNTEERING, YOUTH EMPOWERMENT FOUNDATION

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIP

Collection of donations for people who were in need in lockdown. Spreading awareness about our organization to people who don't know about it.

EDUCATION

APRIL (2017) - SEPTEMBER (2021)

B. TECH (HONS.), COMPUTER SCIENCE, BHARTIYA INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING &

TECHNOLOGY

Percentage: 77.00%

YEAR OF COMPLETION: 2017

SENIOR SECONDARY (XII), NARAYANA JUNIOR COLLEGE (TELANGANA BOARD)

Percentage: 88.70%

YEAR OF COMPLETION: 2015

SECONDARY (X), TAGORE INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL (CBSE BOARD)

CGPA: 8.00/10

PROJECTS

- Library Management System (Python)
- <u>Color Detection (Python)</u>
- Real Estate Company prediction (Machine Learning)
- Voice assistant (Python)
 - Flappy Bird (Pygame)
- Fake News Detection (Machine Learning)

SKILLS

- C Programming
- Algorithm
- Data Structure
- Excel

- Python
- HTML
- English Proficiency (Spoken)